hipstamatic.com 2012-03-11

# HipstaMart

Hipstamatic.com recognizes that its customers, visitors, users and others (known collectively or individually as "Users") who use www.Hipstamatic.com (the "Website") value their privacy. This Privacy Policy applies to all the products, services, and websites offered by Synthetic, LLC, as owner of Hipstamatic.com (“Synthetic”, “we” or “us”), and details important information regarding the use and disclosure of User information collected on the Website.

Your use of the Website and any personal information you provide on the Website remains subject to the terms of this Privacy Policy and our Terms of Use Agreement. Please open the following link to review the applicable Terms of Use Agreement: <http://community.hipstamatic.com/general_terms>

Our Privacy Policy applies only to websites and services that are owned and operated by Synthetic. While other websites may be displayed as links from within Hipstamatic.com, those sites are owned and operated by others, and they may have different privacy policies. When linking from Hipstamatic.com to other websites, if you have privacy concerns, we urge you to review the privacy policies of those sites.

* ### Information Collection and Use

#### General

Hipstamatic.com does not require that you register in order to view its products or, in most cases, User comments or submissions. Registration is required to use certain interactive features such as submitting photos to the contest and managing prints and placing orders. We currently use Facebook Connect and Twitter for voting and commenting. We collect personal information when you register with Hipstamatic.com, when you visit the Website, when you make a purchase, or any time you provide information to us. We may combine information about you that we have with information we obtain from business partners or other companies.

Synthetic automatically receives and records other non-personally-identifying information ("Non-Personal Information") on our server logs from your browser even if you do not register with Hipstamatic.com. For example, your IP address, Hipstamatic.com cookie information, and the pages you visit are recorded on our server log.

We use Non-Personal Information for the following general purposes: to customize the advertising and content you see, improve our services, conduct research, and provide anonymous reporting for internal and external clients.

#### Registration

In order to participate on this Website, we request certain personally identifiable information from you (“Personally Identifiable Information”) on the registration form and require you to create a user name and password. During registration you are required to give contact information (such as name and email address). We use Personally Identifiable Information to contact you about the services on our site in which you have expressed interest. When you register with Hipstamatic.com and sign in to our services, you are not anonymous to us.

You have the option to provide demographic information (such as gender, birth date and general location) to us; we encourage you to submit this information to us so we can provide you a more personalized experience on our site.

During registration, you can choose to opt into our newsletter as well as periodic email updates from our Website regarding newly printed designs, new products, and upcoming sales on our Website.

Synthetic is the sole owner of the information collected on its websites. We collect Personally Identifiable Information from our Users at several different points on our Website. 

#### Orders

If you purchase a product or service from us, we request certain Personally Identifiable Information from you on our order form. You must provide contact information (such as name, email and shipping address) and financial information (such as credit card number, expiration date and the 3 digit security code). We use Personally Identifiable Information for billing purposes and to fill your orders. If we have trouble processing an order, we will use this information to contact you. We do not store any credit card information. However, your billing information is stored by a third party (Braintree.com). 

#### Third Party Social Networking Services

You may have the opportunity to access or interact with the Services via other social networking websites and services ("SNSs") like Facebook® and Twitter®. Consequently, your Personally Identifiable Information may be shared with those SNSs. If you choose to provide your information directly to a third party SNSs, your information will be governed by the policies of those other SNSs. We don't exercise control over third party SNSs. These other services may place their own cookies or other files on your computer, solicit Personally Identifiable Information from you and follow different rules regarding the use of the information you submit to them. We encourage you to read the privacy policies or statements of the other websites you visit.

#### Choice/Opt-out

We provide you the opportunity to ‘opt-out’ of having your Personally Identifiable Information used for certain purposes, when we ask for this information. For example, if you purchase a product or service from us but do not wish to receive any additional marketing material from us, you can indicate your preference on our order form.

If you no longer wish to receive our promotional communications, you may opt-out of receiving them by following the instructions included in each email or communication or by emailing us at info@Hipstamatic.com.

You will be notified when your Personally Identifiable Information is collected by any third party that is not our agent/service provider, so you can make an informed choice as to whether or not to share your information with that party.

#### Children Under 13

Synthetic is committed to protecting the privacy of children. We do not knowingly or intentionally collect personal information online from children under the age of 13.

* ### Information Sharing and Disclosure

Synthetic does not rent, trade, or share Personally Identifiable Information with third parties except to provide products or services you have requested, when we have your permission, or under the following circumstances:

We use other third parties such as a shipping company to fulfill orders, a credit card processing company to bill you for goods sold on our Website, and an email service provider to send out emails on our behalf. When you make a purchase on our Website or sign up for our email list, we will share the amount of Personally Identifiable Information as necessary for the third party to provide that service, including your name, address, credit card information and email address. We have agreements from these third parties that prohibit them from using your Personally Identifiable Information for promotional purposes.

We provide Non-Personal Information to interested third-parties for purposes of understanding the usage patterns for certain content, services, advertisements, promotions, and/or functionality on the Website.

We use both your Personally Identifiable Information and certain Non-Personal Information to improve the quality and design of the Website and to create new features, promotions, functionality, and services by storing, tracking, and analyzing User preferences and trends.

We reserve the right to disclose your Personally Identifiable Information as required by law and when we believe that disclosure is necessary to protect our rights and/or comply with a judicial proceeding, or legal process served on our Website.

We may share Personally Identifiable Information if we believe it is necessary in order to investigate, prevent, or take action regarding illegal activities, suspected fraud, situations involving potential threats to the physical safety of any person, violations of our Terms of Use, or as otherwise required by law.

If we go through a business transaction, such as a merger, acquisition by another company, or sale of all or a portion of its assets, your personally identifiable information will likely be among the assets transferred. You will be notified via email of any such change in ownership or control of your Personally Identifiable Information.

Keep in mind that any Personally Identifiable Information, or comments that you voluntarily disclose on the Website, for example on comment pages, or on the blog forums, becomes publicly available. Your account name is displayed to other Users when you send or post messages through the Website. Please note that any comment or other content you post or send to the Website becomes published content and is not considered Personally Identifiable Information subject to this Privacy Policy. Your messages and other information you make available in public areas of the Website will be seen by people and organizations not related to or controlled by us, and may be used by others to contact you.

We post customer news and/or events on our Website which may contain personally identifiable information. We do obtain the customer’s consent via email prior to posting the news and/or event to post their name along with their news and/or event.

* ### Cookies and Web Beacons

A cookie is a small text file that is stored on a User’s computer for record-keeping purposes. We use cookies on this site and we link the information we store in cookies to any personally identifiable information.

We use both session ID cookies and persistent cookies. We use session cookies to make it easier for you to navigate our site. A session ID cookie expires when you close your browser. A persistent cookie remains on your hard drive for an extended period of time. You can remove persistent cookies by following directions provided in your Internet browser’s “help” file.

We set a persistent cookie to store your passwords, so you don’t have to enter it more than once. Persistent cookies also enable us to track and target the interests of our Users to enhance the experience on our site.

If you reject cookies, you may still use our site, but your ability to use some areas of our site, such as the shopping cart and design scoring pages, will be limited.

We utilize tracking technology to better understand site traffic patterns and use. However, none of the information collected via tracking technology is Personally Identifiable Information.

The use of cookies by our partners, affiliates or tracking utility company is not covered by our privacy statement. We do not have access or control over these cookies. Our partners, affiliates, tracking utility company and service providers use session ID cookies to make it easier for you to navigate our site, in order for you to use the shopping cart and similar features.

If you click on a link to a third party site, including on an advertisement, you will leave Hipstamatic.com and go to the website you selected. Because we cannot control the activities of third parties, we cannot accept responsibility for any use of your personally identifiable information by such third parties, and we cannot guarantee that they will adhere to the privacy practices we follow. We encourage you to review the privacy statements of any other service provider from whom you request services.

We may use web beacons in connection with e-mails sent to Users, to let us know whether and when the email was opened. No Personally Identifiable Information is transmitted through web beacons.

* ### Confidentiality and Security

We follow generally accepted industry standards to protect the personally identifiable information submitted to us, both during transmission and once we receive it. No method of transmission over the Internet, or method of electronic storage, is 100% secure, however. Therefore, while we strive to use commercially acceptable means to protect your Personally Identifiable Information, we cannot guarantee its absolute security. If you have any questions about security on our Website, you can send us an email at privacypolicy@Hipstamatic.com.

We limit access to Personally Identifiable Information about you to employees who we believe reasonably need to come into contact with Personally Identifiable Information to provide products or services to you or in order to do their jobs.

The security of your Personally Identifiable Information is important to us. When you enter sensitive information (such as a credit card number) on our registration or order forms, we encrypt that information using secure socket layer technology (SSL).

* ### Your Ability to Edit and Delete Your Account Information

If your Personally Identifiable Information changes, or if you no longer desire to maintain an account on Hipstamatic.com, you may correct, update, amend, delete/remove or deactivate it by making the desired changes on account profile page (http://www.Hipstamatic.com/account) or by emailing our customer support at info@Hipstamatic.com. We will make all efforts to respond to your request to access within 30 days.

* ### International Users

If you are a User accessing the Website from the European Union, Asia, or any other region with laws or regulations governing personal data collection, use, and disclosure, that differ from United States laws, please be advised that through your continued use of the Website, which is governed by U.S. law and this Privacy Policy as incorporated in our Terms of Use, you will be transferring your Personally Identifiable Information into the United States and you consent to that transfer.

* ### Changes and Updates to this Privacy Policy

We may update this policy at any time in our sole discretion and without prior notice. We will strive to notify you about significant changes in the way we treat Personally Identifiable Information by sending a notice to the primary email address specified in your Hipstamatic.com account and/or by placing a notice on the Website.  If we decide to change our Privacy Policy, we will post those changes to this privacy statement, the home page, and other places we deem appropriate so that you are aware of what information we collect, how we use it, and under what circumstances, if any, we disclose it.  We reserve the right to modify our Privacy Policy at any time, so please review it frequently. If we make material changes to this policy, we make efforts to notify you here, by email, or by means of a notice on our home page.

* ### Effective Date

This Privacy Policy was last modified December 15, 2011.

* ### Contact Information

If you have any questions or comments about this Privacy Policy, you can contact us at:  
Privacy Policy  
Hipstamatic  
74 Langton Street  
San Francisco, CA 94103  
privacypolicy@hipstamatic.com
